celiac.org 2015-09-05

# *Privacy Policy - Celiac Disease Foundation

Celiac Disease Foundation (“CDF”) respects the privacy interests and preferences of our website visitors. We are committed to full transparency in outlining what information we collect about visitors, how it is used and how you can opt-out of those programs if you so choose.

**Personal contact information we collect and what we do with it  **

When you are making a donation, purchasing a product, submitting an inquiry, utilizing the Symptoms Checklist or subscribing to our eCommunications, CDF asks you for personal contact information such as your name, mailing address, phone number and e-mail address. We may use this contact information to provide you with a receipt or financial report; to contact you to clarify or obtain information about an order you placed or a donation you made, to respond to an inquiry or to send you additional information about CDF. Your contact information may also be passed on to your local chapter.

If you make a donation, we may contact you from time to time to thank you for your gift, to offer you an opportunity to volunteer or attend an event or to make another gift. We will always give you the opportunity to opt-out of future communications from us.

Personal contact information may also be shared with certain vendors, i.e., reputable companies we use for services such as shipping CDF products or sending CDF mail, or providing technology, services, data analysis, research, advertising and marketing assistance and/or content for the operation and maintenance of the CDF Web Sites.  We have confidentiality agreements in place with all such companies to protect your privacy.

CDF discloses personal contact information to third parties or advertisers in aggregate form, that is, in a manner that cannot be traced back to you.  For example, CDF might tell an advertiser how many males between 20 and 30 years in age have visited the Site over a period of time. Information may be shared with third parties to advance celiac related research conducted alone or in collaboration with other organizations or individuals, only after personally identifiable information such as name, address, telephone number, or email address has been removed by our web-related service providers.

We want to be very clear: We will not obtain personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. Providing such information is strictly voluntary. Except as might be required by law, we do not share any information we receive with any outside parties. Except and to the extent that the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (“ **HIPAA** “) Privacy Rule applies to any health-related information you provide to CDF (in which case such HIPAA Privacy Rule governs), the privacy laws of the State of California will govern.

In the event of a corporate change in control resulting from, for example, a sale to, or merger with, another entity, CDF reserves the right to transfer your Personal Information to the new party in control or the party acquiring assets. In the event of such a change, your Personal Information will continue to be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy unless any changes to the Privacy Policy are made in accordance with the section below that discusses “Changes to This Privacy Policy.”

**Personal billing information we collect and what we do with it**

In addition to personal contact information, we ask for billing information, such as your billing address and credit card number, when you make a donation or purchase a product. We use secure servers to gather and process your billing information. These secure servers are hosted by our agent, Blackbaud, which is bound by our site policies. Your billing information is not shared with any other organizations, and your credit card number is not retained once your transaction has been authorized and processed.

**Other contact information we collect and what we do with it**

In some instances, we ask for contact information for people other than yourself including, for example, e-mail addresses of friends to whom you send e-cards or a copy of one of our Web pages, or the mailing address of someone you wish us to notify of a donation you have made. The information we collect is used to send the donation notification or information you requested and/or to inform the recipient of the opportunity to subscribe to receive CDF updates and opportunities to get involved. Such contact information is not shared with any outside parties.

**How to view or change your information**

If you wish to opt out of future eCommunications from CDF, you may log in to your CDF portal account and select Email Preferences.  You may also make changes to information you have given us by selecting My Profile.

Also, with the exception of credit card numbers, which are not retained, you can view and request changes to all the information you have given us, including any mailing lists you may be on, by contacting us.

Celiac Disease Foundation  
Attention: Donor Relations  
20350 Ventura Blvd., Ste. 240  
Woodland Hills, CA 91364

E-mail address:  [info@celiac.org](mailto:info@celiac.org)

In addition, if you have subscribed to CDF eCommunications, you can unsubscribe by clicking on the Email Preferences link featured at the end of the newsletter.

**Normal browsing**

CDF does not collect any personally identifying information from you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide such information to us.

You can browse the CDF website without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself. The information we gather during normal browsing comes from two sources: (1) standard server logs collect information such as the IP (Internet Protocol) address, domain name, browser type, operating system and information like the site that referred you to us, the files you downloaded, the pages you visited and the dates/times of those visits; and (2) if you have come into the website from one of one of our newsletters or from a site that has requested a link, we will ask your browser to accept a “cookie” (defined below) that carries a general marketing source code with you as you browse through the website, in order to help us match referring sites to donations made. This cookie does not capture or hold any personally identifying information about you, and is deleted when you end your session by leaving our website or closing your browser.

**Cookies**

When you visit our website, we might store some information on your computer in the form of a “cookie” (i.e., a small piece of data that stores information on your browser in your computer’s hard drive) or similar file. We use conversion tracking cookies as part of campaigns in order to analyze trends, gather broad demographic information and monitor website traffic patterns that can help us further develop and improve the design and functionality of our site. Similarly, we also use cookies for “retargeting” in our Internet advertising campaigns so that third party vendors, including Google, can show you advertising about CDF as you browse the Internet. Retargeting is a marketing tool that identifies you as a previous visitor to the CDF website and targets you for specific outreach messages, encouraging you to revisit our website or consider donating. The cookies will only be used to obtain non-personal information (you will be anonymous). If you prefer, you can usually set your browser to refuse cookies, or to notify you when you receive a new cookie. You can also opt out of receiving cookies on the CDF website for Google advertising by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page (http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/#toc-edit).

**Links to other sites**

This website contains links to other sites, including ones that may gather personal contact information. CDF is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such websites. However, any personal information obtained by us through other sites is treated as if it was gathered on our site and our privacy policy applies.

**Children**

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. You should be aware that this Site is not intended or designed to attract children under the age of 13. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we actually know is a child under the age of 13.

**Changes to this policy**

Our Privacy Policy is subject to change from time to time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this Web page, and we will mark the link to our updated Privacy Policy on the home page of this website to note the date of any changes so that you will always know what information we collect, how we use it and what choices you have.

Thank you for taking the time to review our Privacy Policy.  If you have any questions about these policies, or your dealings with this website, you can contact:

**Celiac Disease Foundation**  
20350 Ventura Blvd., Ste. 240  
Woodland Hills, CA 91364  
818.716.1513

Or you may fill out our Contact Us form
